Hello friends, my name is Abhishek and
welcome to my channel Invest in Shore.
Friends, today in this video we will cover the
Smart Term Plan of ICS Prudential Life Insurance. Yes
friends, I am talking about the
Protect and Gain Plan of ICS Prudential. In
which if something happens to a person
during the policy term, then his
family gets a good sum insured
amount. And if nothing happens to his policy
term, then he gets
a good amount at maturity which he can
use for his retirement life.
Earlier, last week we
covered the Smart Term Plan of ICS Life Insurance. So
if you have not seen that video yet, then definitely watch
that video after this video.
We have given the link in the i button,
you can watch it. So let's move on
and understand this product
in detail. Before moving ahead in the video,
friends, don't forget to subscribe to our channel
because in the upcoming videos we will
understand more which plan is there which you
can take for yourself. So let's cover this
ICS Potential Plan in details
first.  Let's talk about the entry age, friends.
In this product, the minimum entry age is 18
years and the maximum entry age is 60 years.
If I talk about the maturity age, then the
minimum maturity age is 48 years
and the maximum maturity age is 90 years. If I
talk about the policy term, then the minimum policy
term is 30 years and the maximum policy
term is 40 years, which means that you get only two
options, 30 years and 40 years.
No option of 35 or 36 is being given in between. If I
talk about the premium payment option, then
here you only get the option of limited pay. The option of
single pay or regular pay is
not being given. If I
talk about the premium payment term, then here the company is
giving the option of premium payment from five years to 12 years. If I talk about the
premium payment frequency, then
here the option of monthly, half yearly and annual is being given. The
option of quarterly is
not available. If I talk about the plan option, then
here the company gives you two types of plans - life and growth.  The company
is offering the option of a plan of Rs. 10 lakh. In life,
you basically have to choose the sum assured,
whereas in growth, you have to choose the premium and
accordingly you
get the policy. If I talk about the minimum assured premium, then
here if you are taking a life plan, then the
minimum premium is Rs. 40,000.
In growth, the minimum premium is Rs. 1.25 lakh.
Talking about sum assured, in life option, the minimum sum assured is Rs.
4 lakh and in growth, the
minimum sum assured is Rs. 12.5 lakh. If I
talk about maturity age, then here if
nothing happens to a person till the policy term, then whatever is the
fund value at maturity, he is given the policy and the
policy closes there itself. If I
talk about death benefit, then here if you
look at the next screen, the company has
given the option of higher of the three, that is, the sum
assured fund value or the minimum death
benefit, whichever is the highest among these three, is
given to the nominee.
Now let's talk about investment options.  As for what is
given in this product, here the
company is giving you two investment
options. The first one is simple. They have 22
funds which we have given on the screen. Out of
these, you can choose any fund in any proportion
and that
investment gets made in it. Whatever your
premium comes, you
get returns accordingly. Secondly, you
can customize your investment by
choosing a portfolio strategy. So here
again the company is giving you four options -
Fixed Portfolio Strategy, Target Asset
Allocation Strategy, Trigger Portfolio Strategy,
Life Cycle Based Portfolio
Strategy.
You can choose any of these strategies based on your
requirement. We will not cover these four in detail in this video,
friends,
because the video will already be very long.
So, if you want to understand these variants, then
we have given the policy wording in the description link.
You can go through it further.
If I talk about the features, here the
company is also providing you the facility of partial withdrawal, that is, if
you
want  You
can also withdraw some amount from the premium you pay in case
of emergency. However, the company has given some conditions here.
You cannot make partial withdrawal in the first 5 years
and you can withdraw a
maximum of 20% of your fund value in a
particular year. The
company also gives you the option of systematic withdrawal, that is,
you have to decide the particular percentage and
your amount is automatically credited to your account according to that percentage. If
I talk about top-up, the company is
also providing the option of top-up here, in which the
minimum amount is
₹2000000. However, whatever top-up amount you enter here gets
locked for the next five years and
you cannot top up the policy in the last five years of the policy.
Talking about the settlement option, there are
two ways to avail the maturity benefit. You
can take the entire amount in one go or you can take it in installments.
Over the period of next five
years, next is Discontinued Policy
Fund. If for some reason you are
not able to pay the premium of your policy, then the company
transfers your policy to Discontinued Policy Fund. Here the
company levies some charges and after that whatever is your fund
value is transferred to your Discontinued Policy
Fund, where you keep getting
interest at the rate of 4 percent,
which is basically given in a savings account.
Now let's talk about the charges that
you incur in this policy. The first
charge is the premium allocation charge.
If you look at the screen here, in the
first seven years you incur
different premium allocation charges in different years.
In the first three years you are incurring premium
allocation charges of 6 percent, whereas
in the next four years you are incurring
allocation charges of 3 percent. After that,
you do not incur any premium allocation charge.
Now let's talk about policy
administration charge. Here the company
levies
34 percent of the annual premium for the fourth year onward or
maximum  It keeps
increasing from ₹5000000 as long as your
policy is in force. Now let's talk about fund
management charges. Here, based on
your fund, you are charged different fund management charges.
If you see in the screen,
here in equity, you have higher fund management
charges, whereas in debt schemes, the
fund management charges are lower. So basically, the
fund management charges here
range from ₹75 to ₹1.35 on an annual
basis. If I talk about mobility charges,
here the company charges you mobility charges based
on your age. If
I talk about discontinuous charges, then if you
see in the screen,
if in the first 5 years of the policy, if you take the policy
discontinuously, the company is charging you different discontinuous charges in different years.
If I talk about partial withdrawal charges, then there are no
partial withdrawal charges here, there are no
fund switching
charges, there are no miscellaneous charges, and
premium redirection charges are
also not being taken.  Now that we have talked about the
charges, let us talk about
loyalty addition here, that is, if you are
running the policy for a long time, then the company is providing you a separate
loyalty addition, so the
first loyalty addition is
refund of mobility charge, so here whatever
your mobility charges are, that is, whatever charges are being levied towards
insurance, the
company refunds that to you, so
here from the 11th year the company
starts refunding you your mobility charge by 2xing it,
so here if you look at the screen, it is
clearly visible here that the
company has returned your mobility charge deducted from you in the first year by 2xing it in the 11th year, in the same way, from the
26th year onwards the
company returns your mobility charge to you by 4xing it,
again if you
look at the screen here, the company is returning your mobility charge to you by 4xing it,
next is refund of premium allocation
charge, so here the company again refunds whatever your  There are
premium allocation charges which we
told you earlier, first it is charged on 6th year,
then after that for the next 4 years
you are charged on 3rd year, so again the company
adds 2x the amount to your fund value in the form of units from the 11th year onward.
Next is maturity booster. So if
you continue the policy till your full policy term, then
the company is
also providing you the benefit of maturity booster.
In this basically the company
provides you extra units which
basically means your average fund
value remains 20% of the last 8 policy
quarter. Now let's talk about some terms and
conditions of this policy. First of all let's
talk about change in premium payment
frequency. If you want, the frequency of your premium
is like if you are paying annually then
you
can change it to monthly or half yearly. Now let's talk about
surrender of policy, that is, what happens if you do
not continue your policy,
if you are discontinuing your policy in the first 5 years, then
whatever  You have paid the
premium and after all the charges,
your fund value
goes into the discontinuous fund, there you basically
get interest as per the savings account
and the fund management charges of the discontinuous fund which are
approximately % keep on being levied on
you, after the lock in period i.e. as soon as
5 years are completed, then
you can withdraw the money after that, on the other hand,
if you
stop paying the premium after 5 years, then the company makes
your policy into reduced paid up,
where your sum insured
is reduced and your policy continues
from there and you
can withdraw your fund value whenever you want,
now let's talk about the free look up period, that is,
if you purchase the policy
and due to some reason you are not able to understand the policy, then the
company gives you 30 days,
within 30 days, if you surrender, then no
amount is deducted from you, your entire
money is returned to you, if I
talk about the grace period, then here next
year when  When the renewal due date arrives, the
company gives you 30 days in
which you can pay your premium.
If I talk about policy loan,
you do not get any loan against it. However,
you definitely get the benefit of tax benefit in this.
If I talk about policy revival, that is,
if tomorrow you feel
that you want to continue the policy, then the
company gives you an opportunity for that as well. Here the
company has given a time limit of three years.
Within these three years, you have to pay whatever pending
premium is there and whatever
charges are there. After that, the
underwriter takes the decision and accordingly
your policy starts getting continued again.
Now let's talk about the number of funds.
If you look at the screen here, there are
22 funds. We have given their performance for one year, three years and
five years.
Depending on your risk appetite, you
can choose any of these funds for your
policy. So friends, in this way we have
covered all the things of the product. Now let's talk about the
premium. Here, for your reference
For this, a premium has been calculated for a 30 year old male
whose policy term is 12 years and
premium payment term is 12 years and there is a
cover of Rs 50 lakh. So here if you see in the screen, the
basic cover is Rs 50 lakh
and the inbuilt feature is accidental death and
accidental disability for which you
get a cover of Rs 50 lakh each. In this particular policy,
their total premium comes to Rs
5364, which you have to pay for the next 12 years.
If I talk about returns, here
friends, this is a ULIP policy, so there is
no guarantee of returns in it. You
get returns according to the fund you choose, but as per the IAD rule, the
company has to show returns as per 4 per and 8 per in its policy bond or in
its benefit illustration,
so here if you
see in the screen, at the maturity rate, the company is
giving you Rs 14.98 lakh as per 4 per, whereas at the maturity rate, the company is giving you Rs 14.98 lakh as per
8 per.  46.3 lakhs are being
given to you but friends,
you are going to get more returns than this
in this particular product, so I hope you
liked the small information given by us,
we have given the brochure of the product
in the description link, if you want you can go through it further,
along with this friends let me tell you that
we deal in the products of all the big health insurance life
insurance companies
and also provide pan India sales and service,
so if you want to buy
any of these products by joining us, then
you can contact us on the number given below
and if you have any
small health insurance related or
life related query, then you can
ask us in the comment box, we will try to answer your questions,
if you like the video then
like, share, subscribe,
thank you